Guide to the C. Darwin Stolzenbach papers, 1930-1988 MS2028
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Administrator, NCTA [National Capital Transportation Agency], 1945-1972; MS2028 Series 1; 20 Linear feet
  - Public Hearings: Proposed 1-266, [folder 7], 1964 November (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Public Hearings: Proposed 1-266, [folder 8], 1964 November (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Public Hearings: Requirements, PPM 20-8, 1-266, 1969 November 17 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Public Hearings: regarding Bridges from Washington to Virginia, undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (1-695) Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kerman, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 1], 1972 August 30 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (1-695) Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kerman, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 2], 1972 August 30 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (1-695) Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kerman, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 3], 1972 August 30 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (1-695) Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kennan, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 4], 1972 August 30 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (I-695)'Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kerman, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 5], 1972 August 30 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (1-695) Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kennan, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 6], 1972 August 30 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Public Hearings: South Leg (1-695) Hearing, Committee of 100, Letter to Mayor Washington from Peter S. Craig and Robert M. Kennan, Jr., Proposed Meeting, [folder 7], 1972 August 30 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Public Hearings: Statements, memos on DC-Virginia Highways, Contents Sheet and Section A, 1967 August (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Public Hearings: Statements, memos on DC-Virginia Highways, Sections B-G, 1967 August (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Reports: Baltimore Area Mass Transportation, 1966 September (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Reports: Metropolitan Transit Authority, Fifth Annual Report, 1966 June (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Reports: Preliminary Report Pertaining to the Financing of the Proposed Mass Transit System for the Baltimore Region, 1966 November (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Reports: The Regional Transportation Planning Program, 1965 April (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Reports: Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact, 1960 September 15 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Reports: Bureau of Public Roads, Report to Congress, 1965 December (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Reports: Joint Transportation Commission, Comments, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Reports: Freeways to Urban Development, Circa 1965 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Reports: Highways and Human Values, Supplement, 1966 December (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Reports: Budget of the United States Government, Year Ending 06/30/1967, District of Columbia, 1967 June 30 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Reports: Background and Issues, Three Sisters Bridge, Circa 1966 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Reports: David R. Levin, "Federal Aspects of the Interstate Highway Program,", undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Reports: Auto-Train Demonstration, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Reports: Department of Transportation, Federal Railroad Administration, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Reports: The High-Speed Ground Transportation Program, Circa 1965 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Reports: Recommendations for Transportation in the National Capital Region, Finance and Organization, 1962 November (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Reports: Urban Transportation Issues and Trends, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Reports: Institute of Motor Transportation Management, 2nd Annual, 1962 February (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Reports: "Rail Rapid Transit for the Nation's Capital," various drafts, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Reports: Northwest Committee for Transportation Planning, Analysis, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Report to the President by the Ad Hoc Committee on Federal Office Space, 1962 May (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Freeways and Our City, Circa 1965 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Rail Rapid Transit Patronage Estimates, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Reports: National Parks and Landmarks, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Reports: America's Lifelines, Federal Aid for Highways, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Reports, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Reports: "1965/1985, Proposed Physical Development Policies," (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Reports: NCTA, Engineering Plans and Cost Estimates, Report, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Committee on the Establishment of an Interstate Compact, 1959 January (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reports: Washington, A Plan for Civic Improvements, 1947 May (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Highway Needs of the National Defense, 1949 May (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Washington Metropolitan Area Transportation Study, 1952 January (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Reports: NCTA, Conference 1961 Selected Offices, 1961 October (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reports: NCTA, Highway Expenditures and Revenue in the Washington Metropolitan Area, 1962 September (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Reports: The Proposed Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, 1967 February (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Transportation and Parking for Tomorrow's Cities, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Reports: DC Highway Law, Preliminary Survey, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Reports: NCTA Technical Note 64-19, A Discussion of Transit Car Features, 1964 June (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Reports: NCTA Technical Report, A Study of Bus Rapid Transit Operations for the National Capital Region, 1963 July (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Reports: NCTA Draft Fact Book, [folder 1], undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Reports: NCTA Draft Fact Book, [folder 2], undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Reports: NCTA Draft Fact Book, [folder 3], undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Reports: NCTA, Report to the President, Appendix to Volume III, Traffic Forecasting, 1962 November (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Reports: NCTA, Report to the President, Appendix to Volume IV, System Planning, 1962 November (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Reports: NCTA, Comparative Analysis of Rapid Transit Vehicle Systems, 1962 July (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Transportation and Urban Land, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Reports: NCTA, Report to the President, Appendix to Volume I, Engineering, 1962 November (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reports: 11/Report Appendix to Volume II, 1962 November (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Reports: NCTA, Report to the President, Appendix to Volume IV, A Model for Estimating Travel Mode Usage, 1962 November (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Reports: miscellaneous, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Reports: A Survey of Commuter Attitudes toward Rapid Transit Systems, Volume II and III, 1963 July (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Reports: NCTA, Transportation Plan for the National Capital Region, 1963 April (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Reports: NCTA Technical Report, Comparison of Noise and Vibration Levels in Rapid Transit Vehicle Systems, 1964 April (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Reports: NCTA Technical Report, Study of Traffic Control, Train Control, and Transit Car Specification Requirements, 1964 April (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Technology and Urban Transportation, 1962 June (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Reports: NCTA, An Evaluation by the Board of Commissioners, 1963 April (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Staff of the NCTA, Circa 1965 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Reports: The Mass Transportation Survey, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Reports: Commission of Fine Arts, transcript excerpts, 1967 April (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Reports: Commission of Fine Arts, transcript excerpts, 1967 June (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Commission of Fine Arts, transcript excerpts, 1967 September (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Reports: Commission of Fine Arts, transcript excerpts, [folder 1], 1967 October (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Reports: Commission of Fine Arts, transcript excerpts, [folder 2], 1967 October (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Reports: Draft, "Rail Rapid Transit for the Nation's Capital,", 1964 December (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Reports: "Synopsis of Concept Design and Policy for the National Capital Transportation Agency," cover letter, 1966 November (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Reports: Transportation Planning in the District of Columbia, 1955 to 1965, 1966 March (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Reports: The Future of Cities, Circa 1965 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments, Report of the Organization Study Group, 1962 June (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Interim Report, Joint Commission to Study Passenger Carrier Facilities and Services in the Washington Metropolitan Area, 1956 February (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Reports: NVTC, RF&P Joint Study of Commuter-Tram Service, 1965 November (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Reports: The Northeast Corridor Transportation Project, 1967 April (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Reports: DC Board of Commissioners Evaluation of NCTA Recommendations, 1962 November (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Reports: Regional Transportation Planning Program, Appendix B, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Reports: "1965/1985, Proposed Physical Development Policies," (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Reports: Proposed Comprehensive Plan for the Capital, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Reports: NCTA 11/Report Memoranda, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Reports: "A Comprehensive Parking Study," Volume II, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Reports: Analysis of the Continuous Comprehensive Cooperative Transportation Planning Process, 1965 June (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Reports: "Ideas and Actions, A History of the Highway Research Board 1920-1970," (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Speeches: Darwin Stolzenbach, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Darwin Stolzenbach, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: Darwin Stolzenbach, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Speeches: miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Yearly Appointment Books, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Yearly Appointment Books, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Yearly Appointment Books, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Yearly Appointment Books, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Maps: Land Use,NCPC, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Maps: Land Use, NCPC, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Maps: NCTA Rapid Transit System for November Report, 1962 September 25 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Maps: NCTA Rapid Transit System for November Report, 1962 September 25 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Maps: NCTA Rapid Transit System for November Report, 1962 September 25 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Maps: General Land Use Objectives, 1968-1985 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Maps: General Land Use Objectives, 1968-1985 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Maps: Staff Draft, Mass Transportation Plan, undated (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Maps: Staff Draft, Mass Transportation Plan, undated (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Maps: Staff Draft, Major Thoroughfare Plan, 1968 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Maps: Staff Draft, Major Thoroughfare Plan, 1968 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Maps: Interstate Route 266, Potomac River Crossing, 1968 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Maps: Interstate Route 266, Potomac River Crossing, 1966 September 15 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Maps: Interstate Route 266, Potomac River Crossing, 1966 September 15 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Maps: Interstate Route 266, Potomac River Crossing, 1966 September 15 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Maps: Interstate Route 266, Potomac River Crossing, 1966 September 15 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Maps: East Leg, Scheme A, 1966 September 01 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Maps: East Leg, Scheme A, 1966 September 01 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Maps: East Leg, Scheme A, 1966 September 01 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Maps: Railroad Corridor, Low-level Concept, Sheet 1, undated (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Maps: Railroad Corridor, Low-level Concept, Sheet 2, undated (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Maps: Railroad Corridor, Low-level Concept, Sheet 3, undated (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Maps: Railroad Corridor, Low-level Concept, Sheet 4, undated (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Maps: Railroad Corridor, Low-level Concept, Sheet 5, undated (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Maps: North Central Freeway, Circa 1965 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Maps: North Central Freeway, Circa 1965 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Maps: South Leg, 1-695, 1966 September 16 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Maps: Park System of the National Capital, 1962 January (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Maps: Map of the Permanent System of Highways, 1960 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Maps: East Leg, Scheme B, 1966 November (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Maps: East Leg, Revised Scheme A and 4, 1966 December (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Maps: East Leg, Revised Scheme A and 4, 1966 December (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Maps: East Leg, Scheme A, 1966 September (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Maps: Permanent System of Highways, 1965 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Maps: 1-266 Boring Logs, 1969 September (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Maps: 1-266, Potomac Road Crossing, 1969 August (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Maps: 1-266, Details of Informational and Safety Signs, 1967 September (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Maps: 1-266, Potomac River Crossing (same as in folder 2, but previously physically related to preceding map), undated (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Maps: NCTA, Proposed Subway System, Circa 1965 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Maps: Revised Alinement [sic], 1962 December 11 (Box 82, Folder 7)
- President, Metro 2001, 1979-1984; MS2028 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains documents related to Stolzenbach's association with the Metro History Project (MHP) established by WMATA. The documents include computer-generated indexes used in the MHP, transcripts of MHP oral histories, and correspondence.
  Correspondence in the series are ordered chronologically and consists of correspondence related to research for the Metro History Project.
  The material related to the MHP chapter drafts is arranged numerically by chapter, therein alphabetically by type of document. Material consists of computer-generated lists arranging cited documents by categories.
  The material related to the MHP document abstracts is arraigned alphabetical by title of abstract index and also consists of computer-generated cross-referenced indexes containing all the MHP Abstract documents.
  The material related to the MHP monographs is arranged alphabetically by title and contains copies of the three "Metro History Monographs" written by Stolzenbach and Elizabeth Durham.
  MHP oral history transcripts are arranged alphabetically by interviewee. The transcripts are often excerpted or paraphrased, and the format of the documents varies.
  There is also miscellaneous material series arranged alphabetical by folder title.
  This series contains computer-generated indexes and transcripts that generally duplicate those found in the WMATA Metro History Project Collection. The Monographs are a good source of general historical background, as are the chapter drafts themselves, which apparently served as rough sketches of important concepts.
  Metro 2001 was established in 1979, the beginning dates in this series. The ending date of the MHP, and the date of dissolution of Metro 2001 are unknown (hence their absence from the record group title). However, to avoid overlap, documents in this series do not post-date 1984, when the 1ST was founded.
  - Correspondence, 1979 January-December (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980 May-1981 September (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1982 January-1985 June (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 1 Abstracts and Index, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 1 Summary, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 2 Index, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 2 Summary, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 4 Index, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 4 Summary, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 5 Entries by Date, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 5 Index, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 5 Summary, copy 1, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 5 Summary, copy 2, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 6 Summary, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 7 Summary, part 1, undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 7 Summary, part 2, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 8 Abstracts, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 8 Index, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 8 Summary, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - MHP Chapter Abstracts: Chapter 10 Index, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: "America's Subway,", 1979 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: Chapter, "Somewhere Between a Palace and a Grotto,", 1981 August (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: Chapter, "Somewhere Between a Palace and a Grotto,", 1981 August (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: Chapter, "Somewhere Between a Palace and a Grotto," (copy 3, with accompanying photograph), 1981 August (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: "Chapter 1, Metro in Perspective", undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: "Forces that Influenced the Planning of Metro", undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: "Introduction,", 1987 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: "Metro Manuscripts, Segments 1-9", undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - MHP Chapter Drafts: "Notes on NCPC's Transportation Planning History", undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Check List for Subject Coding", undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Instructions Summary", undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Legislation on Creation of Metro", undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "List of Abstracted Documents for which No Copy in File,", 1982 September (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Mass Transportation Study", undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Master List of Abstracted MHP Documents Showing Location,", 1982 August (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Master List of MHP Abstracts,", 1982 November (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - MHP Document Abstracts: "Source of Progress Photographs, Bechtel", undated (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - MHP Monographs: "The Authorization of Metro", undated (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - MHP Monographs: "The Authorization of Metro", undated (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - MHP Monographs: "The Authorization of Metro", undated (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - MHP Monographs: "The History of the Mass Transportation Survey,", 1983 March (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - MHP Monographs: "Roles of Local Officials in the Creation of Metro,", 1983 July (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - MHP Oral History Transcripts: "Harland Bartholomew" to " Walter Fauntroy", undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - MHP Oral History Transcripts: " William Finley" to "Charles Horsky", undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - MHP Oral History Transcripts: "Robert Keith" to "Carlton Sickles", undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - MHP Oral History Transcripts: " Richard Sullivan" to "Hugh Wynn", undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - MHP Oral History Transcripts: Backup Written Copies of Oral Transcripts, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Notes Taken from NCPC Meeting, 1982 November (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Peter S. Craig, Directory, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Director, IST [Institute for the Study of Transportation], 1968-1988; MS2028 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet
  The documents in this series relate to Stolzenbach's research into the history of the highway projects of the NCTA and other federal agencies. The collection includes reports and proposals by other agencies, as well as a copy of a manuscript on Metro history, written by an independent researcher. Stolzenbach used the bulk of his collection, as well as material in other series, for writing the reports contained in this series.
  Administrative Documents series are arranged alphabetically by type of document, therein in chronological order. Included are documents relating to tax-exempt status, office rental, meeting minutes, and other duties of the IST.
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically and consists primarily of Stolzenbach's letters to interviewees and other IST executive officers. The manuscript by Booth Mooney entitled "Metro: Building Rapid Rail Transit in the National Capital Region" is arranged in page order. The Department of Special Collections has also a bound version of this document as a separately-cataloged item.